Antoine Soetewey

antoinesoetewey.com

Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical procedures applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service. In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

Education

2017 – Present **PhD in statistics** – UCLouvain, Belgium

- Thesis: *Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach* (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)
- All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research

2015 – 2016 **MSc in econometrics & operations research** – Maastricht University, Netherlands

- Thesis: Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)

2013 – 2015 **MSc in economics** – KULeuven, Belgium

- Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)
- Faculty exchange of one semester at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA

2010 – 2013 **BSc in economics & management sciences** – UCLouvain, Belgium

Experience

2017 - Present **Teaching assistant in statistics** - UCLouvain, Belgium

- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

2018 - Present Consultant and instructor in statistics & R programming - SMCS

- Statistical and data analysis consulting for professionals, academics and students
- Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates "Introduction to data analysis with R", "Junior data analyst" and "Practice of statistics with R"

2018 - Present Private tutor in statistics and consultant in data science

- Private tutor for students and academics. See easystat.be
- Data science consultant for professionals and companies. See datanalyze.be

2016 – 2017 **Data scientist** – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

Technical skills & languages

Software

- See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)